<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ryan Spletzer</title>
		<description>Software Developer</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Hello World</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/GAC_LifeAquatic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome, my friend. If you’re reading this now, it means you’ve found my blog,
and hopefully this is the perpetual last one I’ll have. I expect designs to
change over time but this content should be around forever. Getting this stood
up has been long overdue, but it is finally here, and boy am I ready to share
some cool stuff with all of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to level set: No, this site will win any awards or blow your mind or change
your outlook on life. It’s a simple developer blog. You’ve seen these before.
Moving along…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s figure out how we got here and the rationale for how I decided to make and
host this thing (so that I can remember it all years from now).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first made my own personal static website back in college in the
pre-responsive web design days, back when I was looking for a my first full-time
job. It was static and had a couple basic pages and that was it. That site got
very embarrassing after a while. I finally decided to take it down and just
forward my domain to an about.me page while I worked on getting a new blog-based
site up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I deliberated over many options, from fully custom developed and hosted on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://azure.microsoft.com&quot;&gt;Azure&lt;/a&gt; (perhaps backed by something like
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.orchardproject.net/&quot;&gt;Orchard CMS&lt;/a&gt;), to paid services like
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, but finally landed with what you see before you
now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a first pass at it and I fully expect things, especially the
design, to change over time, but I wanted to get started and establish a
presence so I can write content about some of the things I see day to day in the
software development and DevOps spheres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I did the typical developer thing and wen with a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;-generated site hosted on GitHub pages. This
required me to roll up my sleeves and get a Linux VM up at home (chose Ubuntu
so I could VNC to the nice Unity desktop for serving Jekyll in a browser), so I
could use the Ruby-based Jekyll tools through the terminal. You can get Jekyll
working on Windows but I’m a big believer in using the tools where they’re meant
to be used – Linux just works better in this case. Hopefully someday
&lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/commandline/wsl/about&quot;&gt;Bash on Ubuntu on Windows&lt;/a&gt; gets fully fleshed out and I won’t need a VM anymore!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll isn’t the only static site generator out there, I was also deliberating
about using a generator called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code52/pretzel&quot;&gt;Pretzel&lt;/a&gt;,
which is a little more friendly to Windows-native folks and has some items that
are familiar to those who write .NET. But ultimately Jekyll seemed to be the
most widely used solution in this space and in the interest of sticking with
something that is widely known and I could probably find answers about in the
event I hit a snag, I decided to go with Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;github-pages&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hand in hand with Jekyll is &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. This made
a lot of sense as a choice, especially because I spend a lot of my time on
GitHub, and using Git. And not only that, the hosting is free, and you can also
set up your own custom domain name in front of it, even with SSL/TLS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But GitHub doesn’t support custom domains with SSL/TLS out-of-the-box, which
brings me to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloudflare&quot;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping to leverage &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/&quot;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt; when I was
looking at the Ghost solution, but it turns out it also works in conjunction
with GitHub pages by fronting it with its own CDN. By using an SSL cert
generated via Let’s Encrypt, I’m able to having an end to end hosting solution
for this blog with custom domain name and TLS, without needing to break the
bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disqus&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and I’m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; for comments. Because why not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;site-design&quot;&gt;Site Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site’s theme is a slightly tweaked version of
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/streetturtle/jekyll-clean-dark&quot;&gt;Jekyll Clean Dark&lt;/a&gt; by Peter
Makhov. It will probably change over time but one of the great things about this
general toolset is the ability to get up and running quickly, and this certainly
has been a much quicker experience than when I’ve worked on my own sites in the
past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything you see here is open source and available in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ryanspletzer/ryanspletzer.github.io&quot;&gt;public GitHub
repository named ryanspletzer.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. I maintain a fork of the fundamental changes I’ve made to Jekyll Clean Dark
theme over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ryanspletzer/jekyll-clean-dark&quot;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/hello-world</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/02/hello-world</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
